cnb.com 2010-05-07

# City National Bank: About Us - Privacy & Legal - Privacy Statement

---|---  
  
Safeguarding Your Privacy

CONSUMER NOTICE

For City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., and City National Asset Management Inc.

_This Privacy Policy is effective as of October 1, 2009._

All of us in City National Corporation’s family of companies are committed to safeguarding the confidentiality and privacy of the information we maintain on all our clients. This notice describes how we manage and safeguard information about you, our individual client, who seeks or obtains financial products or services from us primarily for personal, family or household purposes. It covers how we protect the information which we have about our current and former individual clients.

OUR COMMITMENT TO YOU

City National companies do not share any client information with nonaffiliated third parties for marketing purposes. 

We never sell any client information to anyone for any reason. 

Consistent with our Privacy Policy detailed herein, City National may, on a selective and confidential basis, share appropriate information with another company in the City National family if your trusted advisor believes that company has marketing information on a product or service that might interest you. We may also share select information when you expressly request that we provide you with certain products and services that are available through one of our companies.

This helps us make available to you our full range of financial solutions, including products and services such as deposits, loans, credit cards, brokerage services, investments and investment advice, through our many qualified specialists.

OUR PRIVACY POLICY

It is our mission to provide City National clients, their businesses and their families with complete financial solutions on _The way up_ ® by making the full resources of our family of companies – including City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc. and City National Asset Management, Inc. – available to them. While we do not share information about our individual clients with nonaffiliated third parties for marketing purposes, we do from time to time, as appropriate, share select information on a confidential basis with authorized colleagues within our family of companies in order to offer you financial products and services that can enhance the value you receive from your relationship with City National. 

Unless you instruct us not to do so, our Privacy Policy permits your City National trusted advisors to very selectively and confidentially share appropriate information with an affiliated City National company if she or he believes there is a resource that may be of interest to you. We never do this for the purposes of broad-scale marketing from our affiliated companies, and every City National company is committed to protecting your privacy.

OPTING OUT FROM SHARING

If you prefer that City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., and City National Asset Management, Inc., not share information about you among themselves and with others within our City National family of companies for marketing or other purposes, you may tell us not to do so and “Opt-Out.” To opt-out now, [click here](http://www.cnb.com/optout). If you elect to Opt-Out, City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., and City National Asset Management, Inc., will not share your information except as required or permitted by law. If you do not want any other City National company to share information it may have about you with another City National company, you may Opt-Out directly with that company.

We will respect your choice, even if you end your relationship with us for any reason.

The City National family of companies includes City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., City National Asset Management, Inc. and additional investment management companies. You may obtain a complete list of the members of the City National family of companies by clicking here.

You may also call (800) 480-5443 or contact your banking office or Relationship Manager.

INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The information that we collect and retain is used to provide you with the premier service you have come to expect at City National and to help you meet your financial needs. In the process of serving you, we collect and maintain the following kinds of client information:

  * Name, address, Social Security number (SSN), income and other client information you provide to us on applications or other forms, in writing, electronically or verbally.
  * Account balances or payment history and other client information about your transactions with us.
  * Information we obtain from consumer reporting agencies, such as your credit score and credit history, and from others with whom we work, such as publicly available information or demographics.
  * Password, Personal Identification Number (PIN) and other client information about you that we obtain in connection with our efforts to protect against fraudulent or unauthorized use of our services.

For certain applications, when you visit our Website or use our other computer-based services, “cookies” may be used. Cookies are small pieces of information assigned by a Web server to the browser on your hard drive. Cookies help Websites keep track of your preferences and recognize you as a return visitor. You may browse our Website anonymously by choosing not to provide us with any personal information during your visits. When you browse anonymously, we will not be able to link your online activity with the accounts you have with us.

MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION WITHIN THE CITY NATIONAL FAMILY OF COMPANIES

We can better provide our premier service to you if we can share the information we collect about you among our City National family of companies. We may disclose to these companies all the information we collect about you, except when prohibited by law. However, we limit the availability of that information within our companies to authorized persons who need the information to provide our services to you and to tell you more about them. See _Protecting Your Privacy_.

MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION WITH OUR VENDORS AND OTHER THIRD PARTIES

To effectively administer and service our daily operations, we, like most financial companies, use non-affiliated outside vendors to provide our services to our clients. We need to share client information with these vendors to do this work. Our services supported by our vendors include, among others, printing your checks, processing your account transactions and providing you with online products and services. Each vendor is required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and use that information only to provide the intended service.

We disclose your information to these vendors to: 

  * Establish, administer and manage your account relationships with us.
  * Provide our services to you.
  * Process transactions and account statements.
  * Conduct research and analysis.
  * Deliver our other benefits and programs to you.

As permitted or required by law, we may provide client information to credit reporting agencies; to others in response to subpoenas or other legal processes for regulatory and administrative requests; and to government agencies in connection with suspicious or criminal transactions, including suspicion of elder or dependent adult financial abuse. These agencies and parties may have their own separate obligations to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

PROTECTING YOUR PRIVACY

We take great care to protect the confidentiality and integrity of the information we maintain about you and our other clients. We regularly validate our information security measures and procedures through independent audits and we monitor the security standards of our outside vendors. Within each of our companies, we limit the availability of client information to those authorized persons who need access to it to perform their job responsibilities, and as discussed in _Managing Your Information_ _Within The City National Family Of Companies_. Our employees are required to adhere to our Code of Conduct, which states our expectations to protect the confidentiality of your information.

Our Websites use a full range of Internet security measures. These measures include encryption technology, access control devices, and firewalls acting as barriers between the outside world and the internal bank network, and trusted operations systems. We use anti-virus software specifically designed to detect and prevent computer viruses from entering our computer network system and continually monitor for attempts to break through our information security systems.

We have designed our systems to ensure that your PIN, password and other access codes are private and confidential. We will never ask for client access and account information through e-mail. Therefore, do not respond to any e-mail message asking for your password, PIN number, credit card validation code, bank account numbers, ATM, credit card numbers, Social Security number, Taxpayer Identification Number or other such information.

If you should receive an e-mail requesting such client information, please notify us as soon as possible at (800) 480-5443. We will notify you about our Privacy Policy when you open an account and every year that you are a client. We will also notify you in the event that we change or modify our privacy policy.

HOW TO OPT-OUT

As stated, our Privacy Policy permits City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., and City National Asset Management, Inc., to share information about you for marketing and client service purposes among themselves and with the other City National companies listed, or referred to below, unless you instruct us otherwise. You may tell us you want to Opt-Out from this information sharing by:

  * Calling us toll-free at (800) 480-5443 if you are a client of one of these companies; or 
  * Advising us online at cnb.com/optout if you are a client of one of these companies; or
  * Writing us at City National Bank, Central Operations, 22nd Fl., 555 South Flower Street, Los Angeles, California 90071.

To Opt-Out you must tell us you want to Opt-Out and provide the following information:

  * Your name as it appears on your account(s).
  * One or more of your account numbers.
  * A telephone number that we can contact you should we have any questions.

YOU DO NOT NEED TO CONTACT US UNLESS YOU WANT TO OPT-OUT.

If you do Opt-Out and then change your mind, you may contact us again by writing us at the above address.

JOINT ACCOUNTS

Each account holder may make a separate Opt-Out choice and your choice will be linked to all accounts under your Social Security number. Joint account holders may make Opt-Out choices for each other, respecting information about the joint account. If only one joint account holder makes an Opt-Out choice, other information about the other joint account holder may be shared.

SPECIAL NOTICE TO NEVADA CLIENTS

If you are a Nevada resident, Nevada law allows us to place calls for marketing purposes to our existing clients. If you do not want to receive marketing calls from City National Bank, City National Securities, Inc., or City National Asset Management, Inc., you may be placed on our “Do Not Call” list for these companies by calling (800) 998-0841 or writing to:

City National Bank, Central Operations, 22nd Fl.,  
555 South Flower Street, Los Angeles, California 90071 

For more information, you may contact us at the telephone number or address above. Nevada residents may obtain more information by contacting the Bureau of Consumer Protection; Office of the Nevada Attorney General, 555 East Washington Street, Suite 3900, Las Vegas, Nevada 89101.

AMENDMENTS AND OTHER LAW

We reserve the right to alter or amend this Notice and any of the policies or procedures described above at any time. Terms used in this Notice have the meaning given in Title V – “Privacy” of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (Public Law 106-102, codified at 15 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.), or the regulations prescribed under that Act. You may have other privacy protections under state law. To the extent the state law applies, we will comply with regard to our information practices.

SAFEGUARDING YOUR OWN INFORMATION

It is important that you also take steps to ensure the privacy of your confidential and sensitive personal information. Below are some examples of safety measures you can take to prevent unauthorized use of your information:

  * Review your bank statements promptly and immediately report any unauthorized or suspicious activity to us.
  * Obtain a copy of your consumer credit report on an annual basis. Review all the information to make sure it is accurate.
  * Avoid writing down your Social Security number, your Personal Identification Number (PIN), or any account numbers.
  * Shred all documents containing personal information, such as account numbers, instead of disposing of them.

If you believe someone has unlawfully accessed your confidential information or that you have been the victim of identity theft, please immediately notify us at (800) 480-5443.
